ASSOCIATE PRODUCT MANAGER

Summary

I seek a professional challenging opportunity in the key area of Associate Marketing Manager where business expectations are acknowledged and rewarded. My career spans more than 20 years of business experience. I have demonstrated the professional skill set to successfully achieve both company and personal goals. You will find in me a hard working individual who will get the job done in budget, on time, and within company guidelines.

Highlights

Microsoft Office Professional including PowerPoint, Word, and Excel, excellent communication, written, and verbal skills

Accomplishments

Achieved highest sales volume award in 2006 by providing various sales support recommendations for correct products, parts and accessories to retail accounts and end users

Experience

Associate Product Manager

January 2011 to Current American Express il/4 Seattle, WA

- Work closely with Marketing to help develop and ensure accurate and timely sales literature, training material and numerous other collateral materials while coordinating with China suppliers.
- Support sales management providing product information to account managers, store & field sales reps Dependable resource for sales
 account managers participating in numerous consumer and contractor trade shows and National Sales meeting Lead product development
 team to release units to NAFTA market Headed up field testing with multiple Titan Reps working closely with engineering & quality on
 internal testing efforts Lead HVLP project team for sustaining HVLP activity; pursued HVLP product line rationalization; qualified new
 supplier for newly configured Wagner HVLP conversion gun, initiate product improvement requests Lead Titan Impact & Advantage large
 electric piston pump project team for sustaining piston pump activity.

Tech Service/Sales Support Rep

January 2005 to January 2011 Maximus, Inc. il/4 Abilene, TX

• Provide highly technical guidance for various Wagner product lines via training sessions to in house staff, field service centers, sales reps and end users Selected as the lead person in the department to tackle special management projects to determine the scope of the issue, analyze, offer recommendations and present findings Completed voice overs and video shoots for numerous Wagner consumer products working with Christine Weller Creative (Australia), Take 1 Productions, and voice recordings for all Customer Service; live radio interview with The Country Life Worked with Marketing to complete numerous photo shoots for Wagner consumer products for packaging artwork Make product presentations and demo's at National, Regional, and Customer trade shows for all Wagner consumer product categories Achieved highest sales volume award in 2006 by providing various sales support recommendations for correct products, parts and accessories to retail accounts and end users Attend and support sales managers at various key account calls Train new employees in technical service/sales support functions Serve as account manager for service agencies with orders & policies regarding Wagner products Effectively take all escalated problem calls in the department to offer solutions for end users, retail stores, and service agencies for total customer satisfaction.

Customer Service Representative

January 2000 to January 2001 Maximus, Inc. il/4 Anaheim, CA

- Recognized as the leading sales consultant selling cell phones, pagers, telephones, and equipment.
- Balanced cash drawers/received customer payments.
- Phone service & Internet access/resolved customer related concerns.

Customer Service Representative

January 1984 to January 2000 Citizens Bank And Trust Company il City, STATE

- Tracked insurance for installment loan collateral.
- Reconciled bank accounts/telephone switchboard for over 50 people.
- Opened new accounts, safe deposit boxes, issued bonds, CD's etc.
- Resolved numerous customer-related concerns/various other duties.

Education

3 1982 Des Moines Area Community College GPA: GPA: 3.85 GPA: 3.85 College graduate with strong academic skills and hands-on experience planning projects and presentations - Team player; interact well with co-workers and management - completed numerous courses in Marketing, Product Management, Human Resources, Communications, etc.

B.S : Business Administration Management , 12 2004 Southwest Minnesota State University GPA: GPA: 3.77 Business Administration GPA: 3.77 Management

Skills

academic, photo, bonds, CD, excellent communication, consultant, conversion, customer satisfaction, Customer Service, Dependable, product development, Human Resources, insurance, Internet access, market, Marketing, materials, Excel, Microsoft Office Professional, PowerPoint, Word, packaging, policies, presentations, Product Management, quality, radio, retail, selling, Sales, sales management, sales support, switchboard, Team player, telephone, telephones, phones, Phone, trade shows, verbal skills, video, written